Contact

8336923335 (Mobile) dipanwitabarik3007@gmail.co m

www.linkedin.com/in/dipanwita-barik-3007 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

JavaScript
Front-end Development
Core Java

Honors-Awards Star Achiever Award

Dipanwita Barik

Front-End Web Developer | Full Stack | JavaScript | Python | Immediate Joiner

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Summary

I have 4+ years of experience in the IT industry. Last, I was working as a Full Stack Developer in Tata Consultancy Services for a big Fleet Management company. I have also had a financial services company as a client before that. I had been recognized several times by my superiors and clients for my work.

I am very dedicated and driven. I love challenges at work. I always try to come up with efficient and effective ways to address work coming my way. I always try to meet deadlines and produce quality work. I am a people person and work very well in teams.

I love meeting new people and traveling to new places. Learning new languages and reading books are my hobbies. Currently, I am learning German and French.

Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, JQuery UI, Core Java, Bootstrap, Node.js, React.js, Python, SQL, PL/SQL, UNIX, ServiceNow

Experience

Freelance, self-employed Freelance Developer November 2019 - Present (7 months) Pune Area, India

I am currently working as a freelance web-developer for different clients. I am also working on developing my skills. I am learning Python scripting, Boostrap etc.

Tata Consultancy Services
Full Stack Developer
September 2015 - November 2019 (4 years 3 months)
Kolkata Area, India

I have worked extensively on web-development for different clients and projects under TCS.

Project #2:-

Client: Fleet Management company

Role: Full Stack Developer.

The main objective of the project was to provide 24x7 support to the business. My work was completely SLA based and had to provide solutions to service requests and incidents presented by the business on various issues on their website based on the severity. My role and work were directly client-facing and thus had a fair amount of exposure and experience in dealing with clients. I have deployed several enhancements and projects along with my team. I was also given the opportunity to lead my own team and successfully deploy two separate projects. I have helped the business by automating several aspects of the daily tasks and responsibilities that my team had to handle.

Project #1:-

Client: Financial Services company

Role: Front-End Developer.

My role in this project was mainly to design, develop, test and deploy new webpages for the client or to revamp existing ones. The client's main product was credit cards but also dealt with loans. I have assisted in creating webpages for onboarding new customers and landing pages for the client. I had created an automated tool in Excel using VB to reduce my team's efforts on repetitive and tedious tasks.

Awards and recognition: I have been awarded the 'Star Achiever Award' twice. My work has recognized and appreciated by my supervisors, leads, and clients on various occasions.

Education

Calcutta University, Kolkata

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science · (2011 - 2014)